ice.org.uk 2015-10-19

# Privacy policy - Institution of Civil Engineers (ICE)

## Privacy policy

Any personal information collected on ICE websites is protected under the eight data protection principles outlined in the Data Protection Act 1998. These principles protect the reasonable and lawful use of personal data without infringing user privacy.

Data we hold will be used confidentially, and to help us run our services and keep you informed - for example, to collect subscriptions, mail out publications and let you know about conferences and events. Members' names and grade of membership are published on the on-line Members’ Directory.

We may also share relevant data to third parties, but only those that been carefully screened, and can offer members and customers useful information and services. The revenue we receive from third parties helps us improve and enhance our services. Members' data will also be shared with the [ICE Benevolent Fund](http://www.icebenfund.com/).

Overseas members may have their data transferred to international country representatives, to help them administer local events in their home country. We may also use relevant information to target and promote journals, training, and recruitment services.

If you don't want to receive such information, please let our data protection officer know, in writing, or at the email address provided below.

Please note - some employers don't want our recruitment information to be sent to work email addresses. For that reason, you may wish to change your default email address to a home or private email address. Please check your employer's email policy.

For more on the Data Protection Act 1998, visit the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/) website.

If you'd like to get in touch with our data protection officer, here are the details:

The Data Protection Officer  
The Institution of Civil Engineers  
One Great George Street  
Westminster  
London SW1P 3AA

e: [dataprotection@ice.org.uk ](mailto:dataprotection@ice.org.uk)

## Cookies

By continuing to use ice.org.uk, you're confirming that you're happy to accept our use of cookies. We use cookies to:

  * Capture login information and sessions for security reasons
  * Produce more accurate results when you use the site search
  * Track user behaviour so we can improve the site and your experience of using it

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files placed on your computer or in your browser. They help you use and get around websites faster. They also help the site to remember certain things, like your login details or information you provide during an on-line application.

### Can we access your computer?

No! Our cookies cannot look at your computer or read any personal information on your computer or mobile device.

### What happens if I turn cookies off?

If you turn cookies off, you won't get the best out of our website. We use cookies to improve how you get around and use the site, as well as carry out actions, like searching for events or news. Cookies also allow you to log on to MyICE and our online applications.

### Do you use any third party cookies?

The only third party cookies we use are those required for Google Analytics (which allows us to track the site's performance by seeing visitor numbers for example) and other tools that allow us study and improve visitor behaviour and interaction. This data is totally anonymous and we cannot identify our visitors or tell anything about them. It allows us to:

  * See how many visits we get
  * See how long users spend on our site and pages
  * Tell whether users are downloading documents or completing actions such as starting application processes
  * Find out if the content we provide is being used
  * If we start using any other third party cookies, we'll let you know in this statement.

### I want to find out more about cookies

If you want to learn more about cookies in general, and the laws surrounding their use, then [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) is a good place to start is , which has a detailed description of what cookies are and how they're used. To find out more about the law surrounding cookies, [Out-Law.com](http://www.out-law.com/page-5486) provides a comprehensive description of the rules about their use, from both a UK and EU law perspective. 

**Document last modified:** 19 October 2015
